Hey WalletHubbers! Today we’re talking about
whether you can cancel your
car insurance at any time.
The short answer is yes. You will
even receive a partial refund
if you pay your premium in advance and
cancel before the end of your policy term.
However, some car insurance companies may charge
a fee for canceling your policy
before the end of the policy term.
There are generally two types of fees car
insurance companies charge for cancellation,
flat fees and short-rate fees.
Flat fees are fixed charges that do not change
based on how much of the policy term is left.
On the other hand, short-rate fees are a
penalty for early cancellation that allow
insurance companies to keep more of your premium,
above what would be withheld on a pro-rated basis.
Short-rate fees get less expensive the
further into the policy term you are.
Before canceling your car insurance,
you need to gather some information
including your Social Security
number, car insurance policy number,
driver’s license number, and
preferred cancellation date.
Lastly, be sure that you have a new insurance
policy set up to overlap with your current one
so you can avoid a lapse in coverage.
Just note that some insurers require
30-days’ notice before cancellation, so you
don’t want to get a new policy too early.
Now that you know a bit more
about canceling car insurance,
you’re ready to start the
transition to a new insurer.
To check out WalletHub’s guide to switching car
insurance companies, just click the button here.